<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "${ent.filename}">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter id="design_overview">

	<title>Architecture</title>

	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is based on robust and proven &THIS.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE 1.1 Server and &THIS.PLATFORM; jSS7 Stack.
	</para>

	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; JAIN SLEE Server is a highly scalable event-driven application server with a robust component model and fault tolerant execution environment. 
		It provides a set of connectors to a variety of networks elements: SS7 MAP, TCAP, INAP, ISUP, SMPP, XMPP, SIP, MGCP, HTTP, XDM, XCAP, Diameter and many others. 
		It is fully compliant with JSR 240 (JSLEE 1.1).
	</para>

	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; jSS7 is a software based implementation of the SS7 protocol. It provides implementation for Level 2 and above in the SS7 protocol Stack. &THIS.PLATFORM;
		jSS7 Stack User Guide is bundled within and you can refer to the guide for more details on the Stack.
	</para>

	<para>The diagram below depicts top design overview:</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/ussd-application-design-overview.png" format="PNG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.APPLICATION;
				Design overview
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>

	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; provides Load Balancing and Fault Tolerance. 
		Two or more third-party Application Servers can be paired to provide Fault-Tolerance on the Gateway and GSM Network level.
	</para>
	<para>Geographic Redundancy can be achieved as shown in the diagram below:</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/MultipleGeoghraphicSite.png" format="PNG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.APPLICATION; load balanced and high availability deployment - Geographic Redundancy
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	
	<para>
		Below diagram shows how to achieve load-balancing by connecting to two STP's from Operator side.
	</para>
	
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/Load-balanced-USSD-Topology.png" format="PNG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.APPLICATION; load balanced and high availability deployment
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
		
	<important>
		<para>As of now, the Gateway supports the following protocols for proxying:
		</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<acronym>HTTP</acronym>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<acronym>SIP</acronym>
				</para>
			</listitem>			
		</itemizedlist>
	</important>

</chapter>

